[Music]
Hello friends, my name is Ramkishan and
today I want to give you some basic information about the post that has been announced in the bank,
like in which
bank the post has been announced, what is the
name of that post,
if I have to apply for that post then what
qualification is required, what is the further
limit in that post,
what is the minimum requirement in that post, is
experience in banking necessary for that post,
how many hours of duty will I have to do in that post and what
type of duty will it be,
how much salary will I get in that post, if I have to
join that post then
what will be the process for joining, so
I want to clear all these questions or any doubt that you have in your mind regarding this post from the basic point of view, so
you must watch this video from the beginning
till the end so that you have detailed information about this post, the
basic details that
I am going to tell you about, so
yes my dear mandate
friends, the
name of the bank for that post that has been announced is ICICI Bank
And in this ICICI Bank, a
general post has been announced. Aryan means
relationship management or we can
also call it just relation manager.
What is required in a relationship manager?
Some basic information.
Your marks should be at least 50% plus in all three classes.
If your
marks are less than 50% in any one of the three classes, then you cannot apply for this post. So,
I have already told you about the qualification that you should have
50% marks in tenth,
50% marks in twelfth and 50% marks in other graduation. Next is
compulsory.
In this, your age should be at least 21 years and maximum
26 years. If your age is more than 26 years, then
you cannot apply for this post
and if it is less than 26 years, then you
can apply for it. The next question arises
that sir, is it necessary to have experience in the banking sector for this general post?
So my dear mandate friends, let me tell you that no
kind of experience is necessary for this general post
in this post.
Freshers can also apply
but the
person whose talking
skills, which we call communication skills, should be
a little good or you
feel that yes, I can do my skills which are strong,
such a person can apply for this post
but it is
not necessary that you have knowledge about the banking sector
or experience, this is
not necessary right now, I hope
you must have understood
that how much qualification is required, how much is being
demanded in this post and whether experience is required in this post, I hope
you must have understood that
freshers can also apply for this post, okay
next let's talk about this,
we are talking about arm post or
relationship management post,
what actually has to be done in this post, what is it, a
little
information about it
means
bank, see, there are many products in the banking sector, there are
many products in the banking sector,
like if you go to a mobile shop,
then there are mobile phones, all the people
[Music]
Mobile phones of many companies are sold from a single shop,
similarly in a single bank, there are
many products of the bank,
like
insurance is one of its products,
like account is a product, current account
is a product, there are many such personal loans, home
loan
sector, there are many such products in the banking sector
too, which have to be sold,
what do you have to do, now it is
not that you have to go to the market and
sell it, first understand the importance of mango, mango is
such a post
in the banking sector,
which is also called responsibility post,
in the banking sector, mango post has a
huge responsibility in a bank
and it is also seen from the point of view of respect and honor, the
person who is there or the relationship manager,
under him there are sales officers or
sales executives, such people work, they
tell such people how to work, so
in itself this is a very good post and a
respected and responsible post,
okay, so
how do you have to perform your duty in mango post, the
duty is not such that you go to the bank in the morning at
9:30 or 10:00 and in the evening  It is
not that in this post you have to do
most of your work sitting in the bank
but sometimes you have to go to the field as well
because in this you have to deal with people who are in good positions
or people who
want to deposit good amounts in the bank
or the bank can
also give you a list of people who are
in good positions and have good income, they can also give you a
list of such people that
you have to build a good relationship with all these people
and you have to generate sales from these people, so if
you are under pressure in this way then it is
not that he will give a huge target, he will give only as much target as you
can, the person can exert pressure, he will
give a small target and you will have to develop a
relationship with such good people, whether it is to make
deposits, make a credit card, or
take a loan, that is the
responsibility of relationship
management
and sometimes it happens that some people,
now see sometimes you will have to go to the field as well,
when will you have to go to the field
when some clients who are good  He is in a position
whose income is good and that person
wants to take something from our bank, to take something
means like he wants to take a credit card
or wants to take insurance or
wants to make a fixed deposit, whatever it may be,
that client who wants to purchase any product
and if that client cannot come to our bank, then he has to be given
complete information about the product regarding which he will be talked to
so that he can
buy that product from us, from our bank, in this way that
person has to deal completely
and who can do the deal, the person who will have
complete knowledge,
you will be made an all-rounder, when will you be
made, you will be given training, I will
tell you in the last how many
days the training will be of and he can become one in the training
because in the RMK post only that
person can fulfill his responsibility or
can fulfill the responsibility, the person who has knowledge of all the
types of sales, all the
types of products in the bank, that
person can work in easy posts
and only that person who is good  You can deal with people earning
good income in good positions by
talking to
them well, so
I have told you a little about the basics of how it works. Now it is not that you will
always be in the field, it is not like that at all,
sometimes by chance when clients
cannot come to the bank, in such situations
you will have to go to the clients, otherwise
your work will be to sit in the bank and find out
in the system what a person needs, who
needs a credit card, who needs insurance, if
I talk to whom I can make a fixed
deposit, all such things have to be done with less
management and
build relationships with people earning good income in good positions,
this is the type of work in it,
which I have told you a little about the basics
and your duty is like the bank's work, the
bank's official time,
now let us talk about the salary, sir,
what will be the salary in it, will
you get it in your block itself or will you get it in the
vicinity of your village, I will
not comment on this, but in the
branch where the post is available in your district, you should get it
in the branch  The
bank will post you, okay, and the
salary is like this: if you are
posted in a small branch, then the
minimum
salary that you will get will be
16,000 plus,
and if you are posted in a city where there is a
business hub, if
you are
posted in such a place, then your
salary there will be 20,000 plus, so the
minimum
package is from 2,45,000 to 2,99,000. The annual
package is
okay, so this salary depends on you,
how are your skills,
your salary will also increase gradually, and if
you want, what is there in the banking field, there are
promotions very quickly, and
in the banking field, after 2 years or 2 1/2 years, there are
promotions at good levels, there are
other posts above the general,
like there are some
big posts, which you can do
well and
show good work by removing them.  If you do it, then the
bank automatically
offers you or gives you the opportunity to
work at the next level and
also gives you a good salary. So,
I have told you the minimum salary and the maximum salary as well. In
this way, it protects you
in which type of branch and
in which branch your job posting is taking place. That
means, if you are posted in a small branch, then the
minimum salary in hand will be 16000 plus and
if you are posted in a city, then your salary will be more than 20000.
You must have understood this much that what
qualification is required, what is required further, can you
also do pressure or not, how to do the job,
I have given you a little information,
like the official duty,
I have also mentioned the salary to you.
Now, if you are interested,
what will I have to do to join
or what will be the joining process? To
join, you will have to
fill the form online.
We will send you the link to fill the form online.
After that, when you fill your form online  You'll need to
go to the bank's official website and fill out the form,
which we'll send to you.
After completing the online form, you'll have an
online test exam a few days later.
We'll also provide some information about what will be asked in the test.
If I were to explain everything in detail, the
video would be very long.
So, let me
explain a little bit about the basic
process. You'll need to
fill out the form online. After filling out the online form, there will be an
online test exam. If
you fail, there's an
option to apply for a return exam.
You'll need to score at least 80% or more in that exam.
If you do
n't score that much, there's
also an option to apply for a return exam.
You can apply for it. After a few days,
you can take the test again.
After that, when you qualify,
next comes your online interview.
Your interview will be conducted in basic English. So,
you'll need to prepare yourself a little
for English, as the
interview will be conducted online, either through a meeting
or Google, or whatever.  So basically
you can give your introduction, he will ask basic
questions, you can answer them, he will
ask basic questions, there is nothing to be scared of, he will
not ask very difficult questions in English, basic questions which are usually
discussed,
you will be asked basic questions to which you have to
reply, okay in the online interview,
after qualifying the interview,
your offer letter will be generated, the offer letter will come,
after that the offer letter will come, so the exact condition is
that you are given training for that post, for the general
post, okay, so the training will be of 21 days, the
training will be conducted online and
that training will last for 21 days and in this 21 days
you will be made all round, that is,
whatever types of products there are in banking,
you will be
given detailed information about all the products and because see,
when can you talk openly to people or
when can you give information openly or when
can you tell people openly, only when you have the information,
you cannot talk in front of anyone without the information, so
in this 21 day training you were told the complete details
What are the productions and
how to talk about the product and what will be
your responsibility in the RMK post,
how to fulfill your responsibility,
all the information will be given to you in this 21 day
training, the cost of which is
42000 plus GST, so in
round figure, your training charge will be up to 50000,
through the partners of the bank,
you will be given proper training for 21
days,
42000 plus GST all round ₹50000, so if
you want, you
can also pay for it on a case, you can pay it immediately and
as you say that sir, I do not have that much
money available, then there are
other options for this
also, how to do it
and further information, now the
numbers given below, you can call on this number and
get more details, if
you want to email, then what are its
rules or
you can get information about reducing, by contacting us
Regarding the rest of this post, I have given some basic
information because
I cannot give complete information and I do not even have that much information.
You will get all the information
in the 21 day training itself. Rest,
which post was this? What
qualification was required? What was the further limit? What
experience was being asked for? What is the
job description? I have explained a little bit about the
importance of RM post. How to perform the duty in it?
What will be the salary?
What will have to be done for the joining process?
I have explained all these things to you. I
hope you have understood a little bit.
I am
making this type of video for the first time and
some mistakes might have happened in between,
so sorry for that. If you have not understood anything else
or you need some more information regarding this post, then
you can tell us in the comments below.
We will try to
clear any doubts that you might have and if you
need some information or you need to
talk to us, then we will give you the number in the comments below.
You
can call on that and get complete information. See you
in the next video. Next opportunity
for you.  by taking